Paul Soonsung Kwon

paul.s.kwon24@gmail.com | (253) 230 -8551 | paulskwon.com

SUMMARY

Experienced project manager with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in software languages such as HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, and LAMP Stack while having prior experience in using multiple APIs. Strong product management professional with a certification focused in Project Management from the University of Washington.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Chevron Nov 2013 – Present

Assistant Manager

- Primary role was to support the manager with day-to-day tasks such as overseeing the staff members and providing customer service whenever the manager was temporary unavailable.
- Coordinated the product placement in-store, maintained inventory levels by anticipating customer demand, and handled purchase inventory by reviewing and verifying vendor's receipts during inventory restock.
- Adjusted employee's work schedule and assisted in the selection process for hiring new employees.
- Prepared daily, weekly, monthly, and yearly revenue report by collecting, analyzing, and summarizing data from the POS system.

(Capstone Project) Gilman Piano Factory Renovation Project Jul 2018 – Nov 2018 Project Manager & Product Owner

- Project scope is to plan and execute the renovation of the factory to fully occupy tenants within 13 months and maintain the quality to achieve the highest LEED certification possible with a \$14 million budget.
- Led the team during the project lifecycle specifically the planning phase where I identified project requirements and specifications to create a defined scope and a Work Breakdown Structure (WBS) while developed estimates of activity resources and of activity duration to create the project's schedule.
- Identified and tracked key milestones and project's progress against the project's baseline, identified risks and created risk responses, and organized the project's planned cost breakdown.
- Established user stories and prioritized the Product Backlog for the development of a mobile application and website with a team's velocity rate of 45 points.
- Successfully closed the project on time and within budget while administering the project close phase by collecting project records, identifying and documenting lessons learned, and archiving the project information for future use within the organization.
- Maintained an open communication between the project team, project sponsor, key stakeholder, and the Development Team during the project lifecycle.

Tacoma Central Presbyterian Church *Assistant Director of Youth Group Ministry*

Sep 2013 – Sep 2018

- Worked under the supervision of the Youth Group Pastor that developed and oversaw programs and activities that were directed toward middle school and high school students in order to aid their spiritual development and growth.
- Helped the community flourish by finding opportunities for students to volunteer at local food banks and partnered with YouthWorks during the summer.
- Trained and supervised staff during lesson planning that were administered during Sunday School and Small Groups.
- Coached the high school boys basketball team and participated in youth tournaments in the Seattle/Tacoma area.
- Volunteered approximately 25 hours a week.

(Samsung Telecommunications) JnD Solutions

Apr 2016 – Apr 2017

QA Test Engineer II

- Contractor for Samsung that evaluated their mobile products to verify if testing software accommodated the specifications of AT&T 10777 documentation.
- Coordinated and executed various testing activities in order to verify and detect defects within Android software such as: functional testing, performance testing, battery consumption testing, white & black testing, issue reproductions, and regression testing.
- Collected and delivered required testing information for AT&T software team in a timely manner.
- Improved the device's factory reset test cases and automated scripts to cut overall testing time by two hours and forty-five minutes.
- Assigned to the Samsung Note 7, Note 8, and 8+ projects for both pre and post production.

EDUCATION

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

Certification in Project Management 2018
Bachelor of Arts Sociology 2015

Coding Dojo Bellevue, WA

Full Stack Web Development Program

- 12 week bootcamp with 1,000 hours of intensive coding experience
- Certified in the LAMP Stack

PROJECT MANAGEMENT SKILLS

Software: Microsoft Project, Jira

Methodologies: Traditional Project Management, Agile Project Management (SCRUM, XP),

Hybrid Project Management, PMBOK's Project Management Body of Knowledge